sparebackup.com 2015-07-24

# Privacy And Policy

Spare Backup Inc and our affiliates ("Spare Backup", "SBI" "we", "us", "our") respect your right to privacy and we have adopted this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to explain what information may be collected through this website ("Site"), and through the use of our products and/or services (collectively "Offerings") how such information may be used and/or shared with others, how we safeguard it and how you may access and control its use in connection with our marketing communications and activities. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, because by using this Site and/or our Offerings, you are acknowledging that you understand and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

## Information We Collect

When you visit this Site and/or use our Offerings, we may collect certain types of information from you, such as information that you provide voluntarily via forms, surveys, applications and through the use of various Offerings or participation in various Spare Backup programs. We may also collect information about you from your online browsing and transactions, including your preferences, pages visited, technical information regarding your computer and operating systems. 

## Information You Provide

In certain circumstances, you may be asked to provide us with some specific information about yourself in order to use certain features on this Site and/or the Offerings or to take advantage of certain opportunities that we may offer through this Site and/or the Offerings. For example, we may collect personal contact, billing and credit information when you register, sign up for our Offerings. Please note that the Spare Backup online store may be administered by a third-party E-commerce service provider and the online store privacy policy may differ from this Privacy Policy but the relevant privacy policy will be posted as a link on the online store. We may also collect personally identifiable information in connection with the return of products, warranty and product registration, when you call or email our customer service representatives, enter information on our Site, submit survey responses, participate in promotions, sweepstakes or contests or for the purposes of receiving information about our Offerings and promotions. The foregoing is more fully described below 

## Information Collected Automatically

We collect certain information automatically, some of which may be associated with personally identifiable information, whenever you use our Offerings or Site. For example, when your computer web browser or other communication device (including phone, PDA, etc.) accesses our Site, we receive certain information automatically, such as your IP address, browser type, date and time and the web page you visited before visiting our Site. This statistical data provides us with information about the use of this Site, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on this Site, how long they stay on that page and which hyperlinks, if any, they "click" on. We collect this information through the use of technologies such as "cookies" and "IP addresses", which are discussed in greater detail below. We collect this information in order to determine which areas of this Site are most popular and to enhance this Site for visitors.

From time to time we may also collect general, statistical information about information and data stored and shared through the "Network Attached Storage" features of our Offerings and the Offerings we provide to support "Network Attached Storage" features ("Web Service"). We also collect aggregate metadata concerning your files. We will use this aggregate data to provide you with our Offerings improve our Offerings and improve our general marketing efforts related to the Offerings. We may group this information into aggregate data in order to describe the use of this Site and/or our Offerings to our existing or potential business partners, sponsors, advertisers or other third parties, or in response to a government request. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you or any other individuals.

### **IP Addresses**

An IP address is a unique number assigned to your computer when it accesses the Internet or another computer network. Web servers and network devices identify your computer automatically by its IP address. We collect IP addresses for purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our advertisers, and to track the use of this Site. When a visitor requests pages from this Site, our servers log the visitor's IP address. It is not our practice to link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a visitor's session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us. However, we reserve the right to use IP addresses to identify a visitor only when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with this Site's policies or to protect our services, members, this Site or others.

### **Cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to a device accessing the Internet. We may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on our Site or the pages we use to deliver our Offerings to you. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your device for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. You can learn more about cookies at allaboutcookies.org.

On our Site, we use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate the Site by saving your preferences and to improve and track the overall Site experience. For our Site, we set a persistent cookie to determine your language and country so we can provide you with relevant content. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Site, but your ability to use some areas of our Site may be limited. Please see the Section "Advertising" to learn more about cookies placed on this Site and third party websites.

Cookies and similar files do not contain or capture unencrypted personally identifiable data. For many cookies, you may disable our placement of cookies on your device.

## Cloud-based or back-up data

If you use a Spare Backup cloud-based or back-up service, the information from your device and/or account that you choose to backup such as your contacts, email addresses, calendar, memo, tasks, display pictures, status messages, media files and other on-device information may be sent to Spare Backup or Spare Backup service providers. Spare Backup or Spare Backup service providers may store this information for you and may use this information in order to facilitate or improve the use, remote access and restoration of that data on your device through the Offerings provided. 

## Use of Information

Any information you submit on this Site and/or through our Offerings will be used for a variety of business purposes, including for example, to complete transactions and bill for Offerings; provide you with our Offerings; verify your identity; respond to your requests for service or assistance; anticipate and resolve actual and potential problems with our Offerings; create and improve Offerings; suggest additional or different Offerings; make internal business decisions about current and future offers; provide customized service and user experiences; protect our rights and property; and as otherwise disclosed at the point where such information is collected or in any additional terms and conditions applicable to the particular feature of this Site and/or the Offerings. 

## Information Sharing

In order to carry out your requests, to make various features, services and materials available to you through this Site, to respond to your enquiries, and/or to provide our Offerings to you or enable a third party service provider to provide Offerings to you we may share your personally identifiable information with third parties. Such third parties are companies or individuals that perform functions on our behalf (or on behalf of our partners), such as companies or individuals who analyze data, provide customer service or other Offerings, advertisers, sponsors or other third parties who participate in or administer our promotions or provide marketing or promotional assistance (but such information will be shared only to the extent they need such information to perform their functions). Your personally identifiable information may also be used by us or shared with our subsidiaries, affiliates, sponsors, partners, advertisers or other third parties to provide you with product information and promotional and other offers. Some of the aggregate or personally identifiable information that Spare Backup receives is collected through third party service offerings that are available through our Offerings. In these cases the third party service provider will require you to sign up for the applicable service offering and will include a link to the relevant privacy policy that applies to such collection (i.e. this Spare Backup Privacy Policy or the third party's privacy policy).

We reserve the right to disclose any personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information if we are required to do so by law or if we reasonably believe that such action is necessary in order to: (a) fulfil a government request; (b) conform to the requirements of the law or comply with any legal process served on us; (c) protect or defend our legal rights or property, this Site or our Offerings, or its users; or (d) in an emergency, protect the health and safety of this Site's users or the general public. Except as provided herein, you're personally identifiable information will not be provided to any third parties without prior approval from you.

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell or purchase assets. If another entity acquires us or all or substantially all of our assets, or assets related to this Site and/or the Offerings, personally identifiable information, non-personally identifiable information, and any other information that we have collected about the users of this Site and/or our Offerings will be transferred to such entity as one of the transferred assets. Also, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, all such information may be considered an asset of ours and as such may be sold or transferred to third parties. 

## Choice and Access

You may always direct us not to share your personally identifiable information with third parties, not to use your personally identifiable information to provide you with information or offers, or not to send you newsletters, emails or other communications by: (i) sending us an email at webmaster@SpareBackup.com; (ii) contacting us by post at Spare Backup Inc.,382 NE 191st Street #58973 Miami Florida 33179 U.S.A, Attention: Webmaster; or (iii) following the removal instructions in the communication that you receive. Your opt-out request will be processed within 30 business days of the date on which we receive it.

In addition to your normal access to your web account information, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personally identifiable information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required. 

## Advertising

Spare Backup advertises on pages within the Site as well as on other websites not affiliated with Spare Backup. We contract with advertising service providers who serve advertising to you through the use of technologies, such as cookies and web beacons. Web beacons are small graphic images on a web page or on an HTML email that tell our advertising service providers the Internet address of the Site pages viewed by users, browsing patterns within the Site, and responses to advertisements and promotions on the Site. 

## Behavioral Information/Targeted Marketing 

We also use advertising service providers to help us determine which of our advertisements are most likely to be of interest to you while you are on the Site. These advertising service providers may use anonymous behavioral information, such as how you navigate the site, to provide relevant advertisements to you while you are on Spare Backup websites. These advertising service providers do not have access to, or collect, personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email address, account number or telephone number.

If you prefer not to have anonymous behavioral information used in this way, set your browser to not accept cookies, but doing so may cause you to experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site, as described above. 

## Advertising on Other Websites

Spare Backup contracts with advertising companies to advertise our accounts and Offerings on websites not affiliated with Spare Backup. If you click on one of our ads, you link to the third party website that offers the advertised account or Offerings. These ads may contain cookies that allow tracking of your response to our advertisements. These cookies do not identify you personally. Spare Backup's advertising service providers, such as Google, Yahoo! or MSN/Microsoft, may offer a way to opt out of targeted advertising based on the use of their cookies.

**In addition, if you prefer that our advertising service providers not know which Spare Backup website pages you have viewed, visit the Network Advertising Initiative site: http://www.networkadvertising.org to opt out of ad targeting from participating companies.** In order for the opt-outs to work on your computer, your browser must be set to accept cookies. If you delete cookies, buy a new computer, access the Site from a different computer, log in under a different screen name, or change web browsers, you will need to opt out again. If your browser has scripting disabled, you do not need to opt out, as behavioral marketing technology does not work when scripting is disabled. Please check your browser's security settings to validate whether scripting is active or disabled.

Alternatively, if you prefer not to have anonymous behavioral information used in this way, set your browser to not accept cookies, but doing so may cause you to experience some inconvenience in your use of the Site. 

## Children Under 13 

This Site and our Offerings are not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 years of age. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 13, we will make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our records. 

## Keeping Your Information Secure

We have reasonable security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Please be advised, however, that while we strive to protect your personally identifiable information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your personally identifiable information.

If you have registered on this Site, for our Offerings or are a member of the Spare Backup Partner Program, access to your account will be protected by your password. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to any other person. You are solely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account. 

## Additional Information Regarding Network Attached Storage

Our Network Attached Storage feature enables you to share files from your storage device over the Internet only with people authorized by you. Authorized users have access only to those files you specifically designate. Although the "Network Attached Storage" feature is designed so that no one can access your files over the Internet without your permission, Spare Backup cannot guarantee or warrant that others will not be able to access your files.

You connect with our servers during sign-in. After you have successfully signed in, you can view and download files that you have enabled for web access or that have been shared with you by others.

We give you the option of creating private, password-protected folders and files on your storage device. Except as stated below, your files are stored only on your storage device, not on our servers, The "Network Attached Storage" feature is designed so that only you and the people with whom you choose to share your files ever see your data. Bear in mind that any files or pictures you share using the storage device can be saved and forwarded by the people with whom you share them. We do not keep records of your files on our servers, nor do we track the sharing activity of your files.

We may store the file directory of your storage device on our servers. You use this directory to navigate and select the files you want to view or download when you are away from your storage device. When you download a file from the Web Service, you are pulling the file directly from your personal server, not from our servers. We may also store some directory names (but not file names) in our secure data center in order to provide persistent share information and descriptions to your recipients. The storage device service times out signed-in users automatically after a period of inactivity.

If we suspect that your account has been compromised or is being used suspiciously, we will deactivate the account and notify you.Notify us immediately by sending an email to webmaster@SpareBackup.com if you think your account has been compromised.

All data transmissions between your storage device and your authorized web users are protected by 128-bit SSL encryption. Our service hardware is housed in a secure, access-controlled data center where each access is logged. Only authorized employees with a need for access are granted access. 

## Other Sites and Third Party Offerings

This Site may contain links to other websites that we do not control or maintain. We encourage you to note when you leave this Site and to read the privacy statements of such other websites before submitting any personally identifiable information. Additionally, if you access a third party branded service through an API or otherwise, you are solely responsible for understanding, agreeing to and complying with the third party service terms and conditions of use and privacy policy. Spare Backup is not responsible for the privacy policies or security of third party websites and/or services. 

## International Processing and Transfer of Data

Given that we are an international business, our use of your information necessarily involves the transmission and processing of data on an international basis (including in and to the United States and countries other than the country where the data was collected from you, which may not have data protection laws as stringent as those that exist in your country of residence). By using this Site and/or the Offerings, or providing personally identifiable information to Spare Backup you consent to the collection, processing, maintenance and transfer of such information in and to the United States and other applicable territories outside of the country where the data was collected from you. 

## Contact Information

If you have questions or comments about our privacy policy please contact us by email at webmaster@sparebackup.com; or by post at 382 NE 191st Street #58973 Miami Florida 33179 U.S.A , Attention: Webmaster. 

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Due to the Internet's rapidly evolving nature and/or as required by law or regulatory change, Spare Backup may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, Spare Backup will post its updated Privacy Policy on our Site along with a change notice on the Site. Spare Backup may also send registered users of our Offerings a notice that this Privacy Policy has been changed. Spare Backup encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of this Site and/or our Offerings and/or your continued provision of personally identifiable information to us after the posting of such notice will be subject to the terms of the then- current Privacy Policy.
